HUGUES EBERT MERTILUS

WEB DEVELOPER

786-203-2824
Miami, FL
hugues@vighor.com
https://hugues.vighor.com

ABOUT ME

I am a Web Developer with 5+ years of work experience in building web applications with modern JavaScript & React ecosystem. I turn wire-frames to web pages writing reusable and scalable code base. Experienced in developing responsive web applications.

EDUCATION

University Of State Of Haiti

Bachelor of Computer Science

December 2018

EXPERTISE

IT Support
Web development
Critical Thinking
Communication Skills

EXPERIENCE

IT Support

Aug. 2022 - Feb. 2023

First US Linen Service

- Create website for their laundry (opendoorlaundry.com)
- Tracked all issues and ensured timely resolution of problems
- Trained, mentored and provided direction to new employees
- Technical problem solving dealing with various software issue

Developer - IT Support

Nov. 2019 - Present

Vighor LLC

- Develop websites and applications for customers
- Created and maintained the current website
- Create WordPress and WHM plugins
- Help and assist customers
- Maintaining servers with detailed plans including simulating, testing and setting up complex configurations

Developer - IT Support

Oct. 2017 - Dec. 2022

University Of State Of Haiti

- Implement and use micro-services architecture
- Develop and consume REST APIs
- Ensure high performance of Front-end / Back-end experiences
- Prepare the technical specifications
- Develop websites and applications
- Developed workflows and processes for HelpDesk technicians

CERTIFICATION

Google IT Support Professional

Jan. 2023

Eight-month IT support program developed by Google that covers troubleshooting, customer service, networking, operating systems, system administration and security.

Front-End Application Development with React

Jan. 2023

A course offered by IBM that covers advanced development concepts with React.

Introduction to Front-End Development

Jan. 2023

Course offered by Meta that covers basic concepts of web development with React.